Guide to the Ben Kabakow Collection of New York City Photographic Slides 1958-1980 PR 278
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Ben Kabakow Collection of New York City Photographic Slides
1958-1980
PR 278
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
0.417 Linear feet (1 box)
This collection consists of 686 photographic slides taken by New York City resident Ben Kabakow (1907-19). The vast majority of the slides are of New York City, but there are also a few from Albany and other locations.
Arrangement note
The slides are arranged by subject.
Provenance
Gift of Ben Kabakow's daughter, Sunny Fischer, 2007
Access Restrictions
Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Scope and Contents note
The Ben Kabakow Collection of New York City Photographic Slides consists of 686 photographic slides taken by New York City resident Ben Kabakow (1907-1985). The slides have been organized by subject matter.
Skyline and City Views includes many views of the power plant on 16th Street and Avenue C, just across the street from Stuyvesant Town where Kabakow lived for a time, as well as general views of the skyline from various vantage points.
Hudson and East Rivers includes many types of boats.
Neighborhoods includes Chinatown, Gramercy Park, Greenwich Village, East Village and the Lower East Side.
Street scenes includes 5th Avenue, 26th Street, 42nd Street, flea markets and stores, playgrounds, and other iconic city scenes (murals, pigeons, vagrants, old shack, tenement house, etc.).
Buildings and Sites includes City Hall, Municipal Building, Rockefeller Center, United Nations, World Trade Center, Met Life Building, Friend's School, New York Home for the Aged, Public Bath on 24th Street, churches, Little Red Light House, Grant's Tomb, Statue of Liberty, Ellis Island, and South Ferry.
Museums and Public Sculpture includes the Museum of Modern Art (interior views), Guggenheim Museum (interior views), Floating Photography Museum, The Cloisters and Fort Tryon, and various public sculptures.
Tranportation Stations includes Idlewild (later John F. Kennedy) Airport, Grand Central Station, and Pennsylvania Station under construction.
Events includes the 1965 Pulaski Parade and other unidentified parades, 1965 World's Fair, a 1970 rally in Union Square, and what appears to be the 1973 Korean Fair.
Brooklyn and the Bronx includes Coney Island, the Promenade, Our Lady of Lebanon church doors, general Brooklyn views, Brooklyn Botanical Garden, New York Botanical Garden (Bronx), Bronx Zoo, Bronx River, curling on the Bronx River, Riverdale, and Bronx snow scenes.
Kabakow home includes a few interior shots of Kabakow's successive homes in the Bronx, in Stuyvesant Town, and at 271 Avenue C.
Unidentified and/or locations outside New York City includes a few shots of the State Capital in Albany and one shot of the Amir Center in Jerusalem.
- Skyline and City Views, 1959-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Hudson and East Rivers, 1959-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Neighborhoods, 1957-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes Chinatown, Gramercy Park, Greenwich Village, East Village and Lower East Side
- Street scenes, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes 5th Avenue, 26th Street, 42nd Street, flea markets and stores, playgrounds, and other city scenes (murals, pigeons, vagrants, old shack, tenement house, etc.)
- Buildings and Sites, 1959-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes City Hall, Municipal Building, Rockefeller Center, United Nations, World Trade Center, Met Life Building, Friend's School, New York Home for the Aged, Public Bath on 24th Street, churches, Little Red Light House, Grant's Tomb, Statue of Liberty, Ellis Island, South Ferry.
- Central Park, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Museums and Public Sculpture, 1959-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes Museum of Modern Art, Guggenheim Museum, Floating Photography Museum, The Cloisters and Fort Tryon, and various public sculptures
- Bridges, 1959-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Transportation Stations, 1961, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes Idlewild (later John F. Kennedy) Airport, Grand Central Station, and construction of Pennsylvania Station
- Events, 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes 1965 Pulaski Parade and other unidentified parades, 1965 World's Fair, 1970 rally in Union Square, and what appears to be the 1973 Korean Fair.
- Brooklyn and the Bronx, 1959-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes Coney Island, the Promenade, Our Lady of Lebanon church doors, general Brooklyn views, Brooklyn Botanical Garden, New York Botanical Garden (Bronx), Bronx Zoo, Bronx River, curling on the Bronx River, Riverdale, Bronx snow scenes.
- Nature shots and winter scenes, 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Kabakow home, 1960, 1965, 1977, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Interior shots of the photographer's home, located successively in the Bronx, in Stuyvesant Town, and at 271 Avenue C.
- Unidentified and/or locations outside New York City, 1960's-1970's (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes New York State Capital in Albany and the Amir Center in Jerusalem.